Jonathan, what are you doing up there?
Clark should be doing that.
Sweetheart, I'm fine.
Will you stop worrying?
Jonathan, please be careful.
Martha, my father and I built this roof.
I could walk this roof with my eyes closed.
You know what the doctor said about taking it easy.
Yeah, the last time I checked, the doctor didn't have a farm to run.
Jonathan!
Dad, what are you doing? Trying to fly?
Are you all right?
Jonathan.
That was just that noise.
Where the hell did that come from?
I didn't hear anything.
It was probably nothing.
Dad, look, you don't have to worry.
Damn it, Kell.
I can get you out of here.
I can get it myself.
Kal-El.
Why'd you call me that?
I don't know.
Dad, you said you heard a noise.
What did it sound like?
Just a loud, high-pitched...
Hum? It was the key.
Clark, I slipped and fell off the roof, okay?
Are you sure this doesn't have anything to do with Jor-El?
I thought we agreed we're gonna drop that.
All right...
There may be a huge amount of noise around here,
but you just can't afford a massive US 24 drop.
And I forgot, it's like, what in the world particular?
You know, I'm like, I think it's me.
I know you but I just...
But you know, I think it's you.
You know, I think it's me.
Oh, hey.
If it's you, then I know I t'l l.
Oh.
Get out of there!
Oh, get out of there!
Oh.
Click it.
All right.
We got all the mortar exploded as we broke the door.
Court is almost fit.
All right.
When we are done, then we can't try to figure out
where go the trap.
I'm sorry.
What?
He is.
All right, have the chopper standing by.
All right.
Why did you have to bring him?
Why did you have to bring him into this, Jarrell?
Whatever promises my dad made,
I'll take them on.
Come on!
Come on, Jarrell!
I'm the one you want!
Come on!
Who is that?
Who's down here?
Oh, Clark.
It's you.
Don't let me interrupt you.
I just came down here to be alone.
Yeah, I can understand that.
Sometimes when I'm
down here and I
look at these walls,
I feel as if it might be possible to solve
the mysteries of the universe.
What do you think?
I think it's time for me to go.
Clark.
How's your father?
How's his
recovery progressing?
He's better.
I can only imagine how difficult it must be
for you to...
see him so...
so weak.
Weak, strong, healthy.
He's still my dad.
And I love him.
Of course you do.
A son's love for a father
is nothing to compare it to.
After all,
you only get one.
He's lost his mind.
Come on.
Tobin, we will never forget you.
We will always remember you.
M한다.
We love you both.
We will much...
really...
here you go.
We want you to go to your yard.
You Ray.
We're tiny, but you're my best friend.
Hey, Manda.
Somebody save me
Don't care how you do it
Just stay, stay
Come on, I've been waiting for you
Just stay
I've made this whole world shine for you
Just stay, stay
Come on
I'm having a strange case of deja vu.
Why the sudden resurgence of interest in the caves?
Thanks.
Listen, something truly extraordinary has happened.
Do you remember the octagonal hole or the indentation that was in one of the walls of the cave?
I'm sorry, Dad, that's your obsession, not mine.
All right, but you remember the hole was sealed over?
Yesterday, I found Clark Kent down there.
Clark?
Yes.
And the hole was open.
He'd opened it somehow.
You know, Dad, they say mental illness is hereditary.
I'm willing to accept my break with reality.
Are you?
Oh, Lex, men of vision have so often been mocked.
Galileo knew it was the Earth that orbited the sun, and he was sentenced to death for that discovery.
Where's the Inquisition when you need it?
Oh, don't let Jack know.
Don't let your friendship with Clark Kent blind you, son.
Don't forget it was Clark who discovered the caves.
Then one of the symbols from the caves mysteriously appeared on his barn.
The hole sealed itself up the same day that explosion happened on his farm.
Probably coincidence.
Oh, coincidence.
That's an explanation used by fools and liars.
Lex, we could accomplish so much if we work together.
Don't pretend that this isn't an obsession that you and I share.
We both know that you have an entire archive devoted to uncovering the mystery of Clark Kent.
And if you won't help me, I'll find someone else who will.
I'm on a snake.
Here.
You said there'd be more time.
Who are you talking to?
I'm not talking to anybody, Clark. I'm just thinking out loud. That's all.
Are you talking to Jor-El?
Listen, son, not everything is about your real father, okay?
He's not my real father.
Yes, he is, Clark.
He is.
He's gonna be around this place long after I'm gone anyway.
Dad, what's going on with you?
I don't expect you to understand any of this stuff, Clark, but I...
I almost died. And I look around here and I think, what in the hell did I really accomplish anyway?
You're lucky, Clark.
You won't ever have to face your mortality.
But if you did...
You'd find yourself reevaluating your choices, too.
Like taking me in?
Yeah.
Clark, no, it's not...
I would never regret that. I just... there's so many chances I never took.
I have to live with my mistakes.
Don't let my mistakes be yours.
You tired?
Let's go inside.
Okay.
Last thing we want to do is call more attention to this.
I don't understand.
There's no point in this.
You don't need to be upset.
I'm here to help you.
I'm not gonna lie to you.
I'm not here to help you.
I'm here to help you.
I'm just trying to get a handle on what my dad's going through, you know,
the surgery and everything.
When I was in the hospital, the doctors told me that
depression's pretty common after a major surgery.
He's just not the same dad I know.
Keeps talking about all these opportunities he missed in his life.
Clark, it's gonna be okay.
There isn't anything that you can't recover from.
What if you screw up something so badly you can never get it back?
I guess that depends on how determined you are.
So what's with the cave obsession?
Do you listen to the conversation?
It's one of my father's many eccentricities.
Along with Clark Kent?
Trust me, Clark has nothing to do with my father.
That's not what it sounded like to me.
You know, when the Metropolis police had that noose around your neck,
you offered us full disclosure.
Look, don't try to hang this on me.
Before I agreed to help, all you had on my father was some creative bookkeeping.
I'm giving you illegal cellular research, cloning, crimes against humanity.
So leave Clark out of this.
Hmm.
You've got an entire archive devoted to unlocking the mystery of Clark Kent.
That sounds to me like more than your average kid from college.
Yeah.
Go, Doc.
Maybe if I speak into the microphone, you'll hear it clearer.
Clark Kent is nobody.
A nobody whose pals with Dr. Virgil Swan?
Uh-huh.
Doctor Swan somehow got a big knuckle and èn Talking Ambitious.
A nobody whose pals with Dr. Virgil Swan?
A knuckle the story shall open and smash right in your mausoleum.
What would you call a man with a mountain ofository,
Yes.
a gluttony ,
a man the dead man ?
I'm wondering.
Corporate titans don't often show up at my doorstep unannounced.
Uh-huh.
Then you obviously know why I'm here.
I think perhaps you've been reading my emails to Clark Kent.
Am I correct?
My transgression doesn't seem to upset you.
I'm glad.
I'm a scientist.
I find curiosity to be a most admirable trait.
Dr. Swan, I am the conservator of the Kawachi Caves.
If you can tell me what is written on the cave walls, I would agree to hand over that
conservacy to your foundation.
Oh, thank you, but I'm afraid I can't help you.
The language remains a mystery to me.
Are you aware that at one time there was an octagonal keyhole on the wall of the cave?
It was sealed for months.
Then it reopened suddenly.
Just after our young friend was dead.
I heard you and Clark had been down there.
No, you don't need me.
You need a locksmith.
But the key to that lock was in my possession.
But it was stolen from my safe.
Again, Clark had been present.
So now you believe that he has it.
He trusts you.
Would you be willing to talk to him?
Yes.
I will.
I'll tell him.
It's such a small price to pay in exchange for the answers you've been searching for.
Yes, well, I know what I'm after.
But what do you expect to find?
You're dying.
How do you know that?
As I said, curiosity is an admirable thing.
I'm just trying to figure out what you're looking for.
Mr. Blanck ride.
Where do you plan to live?
There.
Perhaps you could consider immediately.
Dr. BB.
No, Jack, I've been waiting.
I've been waiting.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Okay.
Bye.
urai ooh!
All right.
Thank you for your time, Doctor.
Even if you had the key,
you have no idea what would happen if you put it into the lock.
I'd be willing to take that risk.
Then perhaps there is an arrangement we might make.
Clark.
I'm afraid I've invaded.
I've invaded your sanctuary.
What do you think you're going to find down here?
You tell me.
How'd you open it, Clark?
I don't know what you're talking about.
I don't want to play games.
You expect me to believe your fascination with these caves
started with a term paper assignment?
No. Do it again.
I don't think you want to start talking about unusual obsessions, Mr. Luther.
Unless you want to explain why you blackmailed my friends into spying on me.
I believe that we're put on this earth for a reason, Clark.
Our task in life is to find out what that reason is.
Sometimes we can't do that alone.
You're never going to find what you're looking for.
I'm much closer than you think.
What's going on here?
You guys take the bar, the rest follow me, Martha Kent.
What are you doing?
FBI agent told him, we're going to search the place.
You can't do that.
We can, and we will.
Excuse me, ma'am.
We need you outside.
Hi, Mom. You must be out looking for Dad, too.
I think I have an idea where he is.
I'll see you soon.
Thanks for the phone.
Clark, what's going on?
My dad kind of went AWOL.
He was halfway through unloading the feed run
and just jumped in his truck and took off.
I'm sorry, Lana.
He's never done anything like this before.
Hey, you know what?
It's gonna be okay.
I didn't mean to unload on you like that.
Oh, you...
You never have to apologize for opening up to me.
I need love
Love to light
Please, please
Forgive me now
I see that I've been blind
Give me love
Love is what I need to help me
Lana?
I know this is a stressful time for you.
No.
That's not what this is about.
Lana, I don't want to look back like my dad
and wonder what my life could have been.
Clark.
We've tried this once before.
You said there's nothing you can't recover from.
No, I wasn't talking about us.
Look, right now, think about your dad, okay?
He's the one who needs you.
I realize why they take me
You know what?
siblings.
There's only so much they can give me asali.
I can't take them all I can都有 there.
Although my little brother Honey toi ,
I always think that something isоб
to you over there.
You introduced me to ally sr Something was wrong.
It's okay.
There's always been something
I ever knew.
And believe me...
Clark, I wasn't nearly the son you are.
My mother used to say that...
he and I were like watching two sides of the same...
coin...
duking it out.
And I see the way you and Jarrell fight,
and I wonder if maybe fathers and sons were the same on Krypton.
Except he's not my father, you are.
Yeah.
I am your father who turns his back on you when you need him the most.
I am your father who forces you to run away.
My father never would have done that.
I would have never done that.
I wish I had his strength and his wisdom.
Dad, you do.
Clark, I don't know how to protect you anymore.
It's not your job.
Your job is to teach me how to protect myself.
But that doesn't mean I don't need you.
Mom needs you too.
But I don't..
I need you.
You're family, brother.
You aren't alone.
Lego, you're my brother.
Bob ice-cream is a..?
A father.
Just a father isn't least.
He's being selfish.
And so is your brother.
The respect that you pay him knows it all isn't enough.
High point of your month, but...
I'm guessing something else is going on.
Oh, no. Everything's fine.
Lana, you know you can talk to me about anything.
I want to believe that...
someone can change, but...
But I'm starting to lose faith.
Are we talking about Clark?
Oh, yeah.
He came by the town earlier.
And he kissed me.
He kissed you?
Yeah.
Isn't that what you wanted?
I don't...
I don't know.
Look...
I'm afraid I'm a little jaded in the romance department.
The only thing I know about relationships is that...
someone usually winds up getting hurt.
And you don't think I can trust Clark to not do that?
I don't think it's about trust.
It's like the German poet Rocha said.
A person isn't who they are during the last conversation you had with them.
They're who they've been throughout your whole relationship.
All right, I agree.
ck
I know it.
I know this cell doesn't know me personally.
I just said it.
So those people took me to my psychologicalラ
Mom?
Oh, thank God you're back.
What happened?
The FBI came.
They tore through everything.
What did they want?
I don't know, but they had a search warrant.
The only thing that's missing is the key.
Lawrence went to the hospital.
I have to get that back.
If they find out what that key's really for...
Doesn't matter, Clark.
How can you say that?
Because they didn't get what they came for.
I don't know.
I'm tired.
Let's talk tomorrow.
Can you?
My father's methods are often questionable,
but usually there's a germ of truth in his madness.
Your father's so obsessed about those caves
that he's imagining things that don't exist.
Clark, I'm glad you told me about this.
That means a lot that you trust me enough to let me help.
Is there something you're not telling me?
And what would that be, Clark?
I'll check into it.
What the hell were you doing barging into the Kent farm?
Be quiet.
You're bound and determined to blow our cover, aren't you?
Get in here.
If I want to take a serious look at Clark Kent,
you won't have much to say about it.
Those weren't your men?
We don't make it a habit of stormy farmhouses.
What is it about this kid you're trying to protect?
Liamádraaynes.
What of a kid you always ended up like before?
Flew over here how long we've met.
I thought you brought him in to help.
Cul Dragonallep tho.
Huh?
No way you've seen células big.
I never know what I'm talking about.
And you as a pertinent subject.
She's a good五.
She's a goodlings fly.
She's a obtener of intelligence.
You know the deal. The FBI is not interested in some farm boy.
We're interested in your father. Now get out of here so we can do our work.
Your father's not the one working with the FBI. It's you!
Clark, you have to trust me.
I did. I guess it was a bad mistake.
Clark, you've got it all wrong.
Look, it's not about you. We're going after my father.
He tried to pin the murders at Metron Labs on me, so I went to the feds and I cut a deal.
Look, over and over, I've given him the chance to show me who he really is.
And I now realize he already has. He deserves what's coming now.
And you don't care whose privacy gets invaded in the process?
Clark, it wasn't the FBI who raided the farm.
My father could have had his own men impersonate the feds.
But the question is why.
Maybe he's on to you. Maybe he's warning you to back off.
Look, if that's the case, I'm sorry he got you involved.
But I think you already were.
What's that supposed to mean?
How well do you know Dr. Virgil Swann?
What makes you think I know him at all?
According to the FBI, my father's been talking to him.
And he found Dr. Swann through you.
Apparently you two have been emailing each other.
He's been studying the cave paintings.
Look, Clark, I don't know how you stumbled into this.
But somehow you've got two billionaires keenly interested in you and those caves.
They're your enemies. Not me.
You betrayed me!
Hello, Kello.
My name is Clark.
You think I betrayed you because I met with Lionel Luthor?
Well, you didn't more than meet with him.
You agreed to help him.
I didn't betray you, Kal-El.
I promised you your secret would never leave this building, and it hasn't.
Then my involvement with Lionel Luthor is in your best interest.
That man has done nothing but cause my family pain.
Was he the one who caused the explosion on the farm?
Did he make you run wild in Metropolis?
I opened the door to your heritage.
Because I thought that you were ready.
Your actions over the past year have proven me wrong.
You don't understand.
There was another message in the ship.
From my biological father.
It said I was sent here to conquer.
Do you know if that's true?
I don't have all the answers.
I'm still on the same journey as you are, Kal-El.
Please.
Don't call me that.
I don't even know who that is.
Fathers often want futures that their sons reject.
That struggle is as old as a human race.
Except I'm not human.
Humanity is not only about biology.
Look, you don't know, Jor-El.
Everything that he said has come to pass.
My father made a deal with him to save me.
And now it's killing him.
But the more you pursue this course, the greater the risk.
That you'll expose your secret not only to the Luthers, but to the world.
I can't let my father die for my mistakes.
Well, if that's your decision,
then there's something else I have to show you.
Activate screen.
I'll be right back.
It says, I am waiting.
Must be from Jor-El.
That message didn't come from the stars.
It originated right here on Earth.
But I believe...
that it wasn't meant for you, Kal-El.
I'm sorry.
Where are you, Kal-El?
Where's your father?
She's dead.
I'm just heartbroken.
Death?
This can't happen.
Deeply stupid.
Can't die long.
She's not the kind I want.
I don't want to fight anything that I feel.
Kill me, JC.
You don't want to be killed.
Why?
Why don't you declare her dead?
Are you going to fucking kill me, Dan?
You justneed yourself, NAS&Vayne.
I even got you out of hell.
I can't come to the Владivorz.
I'm still stuck.
I just went to see Dr. Swan.
He thinks Jor-El is trying to contact someone.
Mom, it's not me.
And I think the way Dad's been acting,
I think he's been getting messages through the key.
What would Jor-El want with your father?
I don't know, but he said Jor-El was waiting for something.
Do you know where Dad went?
You searched every inch of that farm?
Yes, sir.
You're certain?
I assure you it's not there.
Why don't everybody get out of here?
Get out of here.
Get out.
Go on.
Right now.
Get out of here.
Leave it.
Out of here.
Now!
Go on.
I said everybody get out of here!
Come on.
Get out.
You have no right to be down here.
Yeah, well, the State Park Service
might disagree with you.
You want something that doesn't belong to you.
I'm not going to let you take it.
There exist in this world some things that are too valuable
to be the sole possession of any one person.
I am sick and tired of talking to you.
This is your last warning.
Stay away from my son.
If you raised your son the way I raised mine,
maybe you wouldn't have to protect him.
You know, weakness isn't something you're born with.
You learn it.
And Clark learned his from you.
Ah!
Gah!
Aww!
No!
Japanese foreign speaking
argument
niin
aren!
Dad!
What are you doing? You're not thinking.
It's the only way that I know you're safe.
Unless you want to explain to the police
why you illegally raided my farm,
you had better let me walk out of here.
Back off.
Sir, you better take a look at this.
The key's in the wall.
It must be.
Where is it, Clark?
I don't have it.
Where is it?
Hi.
Um, I know you got a lot going on right now.
Just, I think we left things in kind of a weird place.
I know the way I've been acting is kind of hard to understand.
But Lana, my feelings for you have never changed.
I guess a part of me knows that.
But, you know, it's like Lex says.
A person isn't who they say they are in any one moment.
They're who they've always been.
Lex?
What does he have to do with this?
I trust him.
I trust his advice.
You know, he only wants what's best for us.
Look, Lana, how many times have we been
standing here avoiding what we both want?
Look, that's because every time you let me get close,
it hurts that much more when you leave.
Look, you can't keep changing the rules.
I'm sorry, Lana.
I never meant to hurt you.
But I promise I'm not going to leave this time.
Maybe I am.
You know what your dad said about looking back on his life
and feeling as though he'd missed something?
Look, I have been so focused.
Focused on you.
Waiting to see if we could ever get back together
that maybe I'm missing out on some opportunities.
Like seeing other people?
No.
No, I mean everything.
And until I figure that out, I can't keep doing this.
It's not fair to either of us.
I love you.
I love you, too.
Yeah, that's right.
I do.
You deserve it one more time, boy.
Oh, come on,funded.
Gary, I look forward to your mom and dad having a fun time
with you and our walk around town.
Yeah.
I want to spend days on Don lake.
Actually, I had promised my
Why'd you go down there with the key?
I'm not sure. I was just drawn to it.
It's the only way I can explain it.
Dad, I know it's the deal you made with Jarrell.
And all this time, I thought that you'd sacrificed your health to bring me home,
but it's more than that, isn't it?
Clark, look, I've...
I've done a lot of things the last few days that I'm not particularly proud of.
But it wasn't Jarrell who did them. It was me.
What's Jarrell waiting for?
How do you know about that?
Dr. Swan.
Dad, what did you promise him?
That's none of your concern, Clark.
Dad, if it wasn't for me, you never would have gotten involved with Jarrell.
Come on. Why don't you let me help?
Clark, I've always told you to take responsibility for your own decisions.
Now why don't you let me take responsibility for mine?
Because I'm your father.
Because now we're both in Lionel's sights.
And what are we going to do when he gets that key out of the wall?
The key is not in the wall, Clark.
You took it.
No.
But it's...
It's still out there somewhere.
If he doesn't find it, you should.
Bart.
No.
I don't want movies forever.
First around kings live in it...
...upperwings talk about history.
Now whose idea was that?
Don't make me laugh till the end.
Little Mr. Shissiri is letting his life go to hell.
He could never longer make his avanzThe Next Top.
You know Jarrell, he still is an téléphone ave.
I can't stand it anymore.
Thank you.